<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-14T01:39:28+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Yalin’s Research Blog</title><subtitle>A blog and portfolio by Yalin Liu</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Research Staff/Student Wanted</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/research-team/2025/02/06/wanted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Research Staff/Student Wanted" /><published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/research-team/2025/02/06/wanted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research-team/2025/02/06/wanted.html"><![CDATA[<p><br /> <strong>Wanted:</strong> You are desired/interested in doing research related to AI-enabled networks, 6G, Blockchain, Web3, and SAGIN. <br /></p>
<ul>
  <li><em>PhD and MPhil students</em><br />
  You need to pass the TOEFL test or IELTS test.<br />
  The excellent students may get PGS: HK$18,500 per month.<br />
  <a href="https://admissions.hkmu.edu.hk/rpg/submit-application/">Click for admission application procedures of HKMU.</a><br /></li>
  <li><em>Research Assistants (RA)</em><br />
  You are familiar with the basic academic tools, including Latex, Overleaf, MATLAB, etc. <br />
  You are familiar with basic knowledge of information theory, federated learning, reinforcement learning, etc. <br />
  Those with a master’s degree or above and published journal papers are preferred. <br /></li>
  <li>Those interested can contact me via email (ylliu@hkmu.edu.hk). <br /> </li>
</ul>

<p><br /> <strong>招聘:</strong> 有意/希望从事与AI-enabled networks、6G、区块链、Web3和SAGIN相关的研究学者/同学。</p>
<ul>
  <li><em>博士和硕士研究生</em><br />
您需要通过托福或雅思考试。<br />
优秀学生可获得PGS：每月18,500港币。<br />
<a href="https://admissions.hkmu.edu.hk/rpg/submit-application/">点击查看香港都会大学入学申请程序。</a><br /></li>
  <li><em>研究助理（RA）</em><br />
您熟悉基本的学术工具，包括Latex，Overleaf，MATLAB等。<br />
您熟悉信息论，联邦学习，强化学习等基础知识。<br />
具有硕士或以上学位并发表过期刊论文者优先考虑。<br /></li>
  <li>有兴趣者可以通过电子邮件 (ylliu@hkmu.edu.hk) 与我联系。</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>Yalin</name></author><category term="Research-Team" /><category term="Wanted" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Space-Air-Ground Integrated Networks: Spherical Stochastic Geometry-Based Uplink Connectivity Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/study-intro/2024/02/16/JSAC-SAGIN.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Space-Air-Ground Integrated Networks: Spherical Stochastic Geometry-Based Uplink Connectivity Analysis" /><published>2024-02-16T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-02-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/study-intro/2024/02/16/JSAC-SAGIN</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/study-intro/2024/02/16/JSAC-SAGIN.html"><![CDATA[<ul id="markdown-toc">
  <li><a href="#citation" id="markdown-toc-citation">Citation</a></li>
  <li><a href="#abstract" id="markdown-toc-abstract">Abstract</a></li>
  <li><a href="#codes" id="markdown-toc-codes">Codes</a></li>
  <li><a href="#full-paper" id="markdown-toc-full-paper">Full paper</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="citation">Citation</h2>

<p><strong>Yalin Liu</strong>,  Hong-Ning Dai,  Qubeijian Wang,  Om Jee Pandey,  Yaru Fu,  Ning Zhang,  Dusit Niyato,  &amp; Chi Chung Lee,  “Space-Air-Ground Integrated Networks: Spherical Stochastic Geometry-Based Uplink Connectivity Analysis, “ <em>IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications</em> <strong>(SCI IF=16.4 in 2022, JCR Q1)</strong>,  2024,  DOI: 10.1109/JSAC.2024.3365891. <a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10438999">[Link]</a></p>

<h2 id="abstract">Abstract</h2>

<p>By integrating the merits of aerial, terrestrial, and satellite communications, the space-air-ground integrated network (SAGIN) is an emerging solution that can provide massive access, seamless coverage, and reliable transmissions for global-range applications. In SAGINs, the uplink connectivity from ground users (GUs) to the satellite is essential because it ensures global-range data collections and interactions, thereby paving the technical foundation for practical implementations of SAGINs. In this article, we aim to establish an accurate analytical model for the uplink connectivity of SAGINs in consideration of the global distributions of both GUs and aerial vehicles (AVs). Particularly, we investigate the uplink path connectivity of SAGINs, which refers to the probability of establishing the end-to-end path from GUs to the satellite with or without AV relays. However, such an investigation on SAGINs is challenging because all GUs and AVs are approximately distributed on a spherical surface (instead of the horizontal surface), resulting in the complexity of network modeling. To address this challenge, this paper presents a new analytical approach based on spherical stochastic geometry. Based on this approach, we derive the analytical expression of the path connectivity in SAGINs. Extensive simulations confirm the accuracy of the analytical model.</p>

<h2 id="codes">Codes</h2>

<p>Coming soon</p>

<h2 id="full-paper">Full paper</h2>

<p>Coming soon</p>]]></content><author><name>Yalin</name></author><category term="Study-Intro" /><category term="SAGIN" /><category term="Spherical-Stochastic-Geometry" /><category term="Uplink-Connectivity" /><category term="Network-Modeling" /></entry></feed>